IAN KIRKLAND

Insightful writer, editor, and market researcher. Seasoned, devoted, and meticulous management of public and discreet marketing campaigns. Expertly skilled editorial and analysis/critique, regardless of content, with a focus on trend recognition and projection. Cogent and intuitive writing tailored to and invested in contemporary global digital markets.

EDUCATION

University Of Edinburgh
 MA in English Literature & Linguistics
 Awarded: First

Edinburgh, Scotland 2018 - 2022

 UCLA French Language Intensive Grade: A, 4.0

Remote 06/2020 - 08/2020

- Northern Virginia Writing Project
 Summer Institute: Creative Writing
 Fairfax, VA
 07/2017
- Fairfax High School Fairfax, VA 2014 - 2018

CONTACTS

Mindy Thomas

Tinkercast Founder, Podcast Host/Producer mindy@tinkercast.com

Greg Stewart

Managing Editor for Theatre Weekly adminetheatreweekly.com

SKILLS

- Native English & German fluency
- University-level French language skills
- Adept use of Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Creative Suite, G-Suite, WordPress
 - iankirkland00@gmail.com
 - **O**7732467811

EXPERIENCE

Podcast Production Consultant

Tinkercast—Washington, DC—07/2022

- One of four writers selected to develop and produce the forthcoming second season of the podcast.
- Conceived of the show's structure, characters, story arcs, themes, and marketing strategies.
- Wrote and presented pitch script to collaborating production company Gen Z Media.

Scottish Poetry Library Volunteer

SPL—Edinburgh—06/2021 - 08/2022

- Implemented the library's new cataloguing and archiving system.
- Wrote for & edited author bios for the SPL website.
- Assisted in the management of library events including publication tours, readings, and open mic nights.

Theatre Weekly Critic

Theatre Weekly——Edinburgh——06/2019 - 08/2022

- Reviewed shows at the Edinburgh Fringe Festivals (both online $\boldsymbol{\vartheta}$ in person).
- Liased with clients requesting media presence at shows
- Published reviews may be found here:
 https://theatreweekly.com/author/ian-kirkland/

Events Organiser

PublishED—Edinburgh—04/2019 - 06/2020

- Planned the society's community events including literary workshops, panels with authors, publishers, and agents based in Edinburgh, and open mic nights.
- Expanded audience from the ground up by publishing monthly newsletters including new articles, event lineups, current event commentary, interactive polls, niche freelance opportunities, and more.
- Worked with SYP (Society of Young Publishers).

Publishing Intern

Touchpoint Press——Remote——10/2019 - 11/2019

- Contacted authors/bookshops, drafted book blurbs & Press Releases, updated media logs & social media (Website, PRLOG, Facebook, Instagram, Hootsuite, Publishers Marketplace).

Lead Camp Strategist

FX Players—Fairfax, VA—10/2016 - 05/2018

- Spearheaded community fundraising efforts by organising biannual theatre camps of up to 200 children aged 6-14
- Raised roughly 10,000 USD per camp
- Assembled camp committee, selected & trained teachers and counsellors, scheduled classes, allocated budget